Input.GetAxis works in a similar fashion
Input.GetAxis は
to GetButton and GetKey
GetButton や Getkey と同じような働きをします。
but with some fundamental differences.
しかし、いくつか基本的な違いもあります。
GetKey and GetButton both return a bool,
GetKey および GetButton の両方とも boolean を戻しますが、
the button is either pressed or not pressed.
ボタンは押されたか、押されてないかのいずれかです。
Whilst GetAxis returns a float value
一方で GetAxis は float 変数として
between -1 and positive 1.
-1 と 1 の間の値を戻します。
We setup axes in the input manager,
軸は Input Manager でセットアップして
which can be accessed via the
それらは
Edit - Project Settings - Input top menu.
メニューから Edit - Project Settings - Input を選択してアクセスできます。
With a button press you'd only consider
ボタンの押下でしゃ、
the positive button value.
ボタンの正の値しか考えません。
But with an axis we should consider
しかし Axis の場合は
the both positive and negative buttons.
正および負の値の両方（Positive Button, Negative Button）を考慮する必要があります。
As well as gravity, sensitivity,
同様に、Gravity, Sensitivity
dead and snap.
Dead, Snap も考慮します。
This is the standard behaviour of
これが GetAxis Horizontal の場合の
GetAxis Horizontal.
標準的な動作です。
Remember that GetAxis returns a float,
GetAxis は float を戻すので
as such it is a sliding scale between -1
これは -1 および 1 の間のスライドする値です。
and 1. The gravity of the axis
この Axis の Gravity は
affects how fast this scale returns to 0
ボタンが離された後にこの値が 0 に戻る速さに
after the button has been released.
影響します。
The higher the gravity, the faster the return
Gravity が大きいほど、戻りは速くなります。
so if we increase the gravity from 3 to 100
このため、もし Gravity を 3 から 100 に増加させると
we will see this axis returns to 0 more quickly.
Axis が 0 に戻るのが速くなることが確認できます。
Likewise if we lower the value from the
同様にして、もし値を
default of 3 to 0.1 the axis
デフォルトである 3 から 0.1 に下げると
value will return to 0 more slowly.
この値は 0 に戻るのがより遅くなります。
Sensitivity is the opposite of gravity
Sensitivity は Gravity の反対であり、
and controls how quickly the return value
入力される戻り値が
of the input reaches 1 or -1.
1 または -1 に到達する速さを示します。
The higher the number the more responsive,
値が高いほど数字はより反応するようになり、
the lower the number the more smooth.
値が小さいほど数字はよりスムーズなものになります。
If we were using a joystick to represent
もしジョイスティックを使用して
our axis then we wouldn't necessarily want to
軸を表す場合、
to feel an effect from very small amounts
ジョイスティックの小さな動作による
of joystick movement.
小さな動きで反応させたくない場合があります。
To avoid this we have a dead zone.
これを回避するために Dead Zone があります。
The higher the dead value is the larger
値が大きいほど、 Dead の値は大きくなります。
the dead zone and the further the joystick
DeadZone およびその先は ジョイスティックを
must be moved in order for GetAxis to
移動しないと GetAxis が
return a non 0 value.
0 でない値に戻れません・
The snap option allows you to return
Snap オプションにより
0 if both positive and negative buttons are held.
Negative および Positive ボタンの両方が押されたとき、戻り値はゼロです。
To receive a value from horizontal or
もし値を Horizonal Axis または
vertical axis simply add an instance of
Vertical Axis から受け取るためには
Input.GetAxis(''Horizontal'')
Input.GetAxis(''Horizontal'') または
or Input.GetAxis(''Vertical'')
Input.GetAxis(''Vertical'') のインスタンスを
to your code as seen here.
ここで見るようにコードに追加します。
You can also use Input.GetAxisRaw
さらに Input.GetAxisRaw を使用して
to only return whole numbers
完全な数字を戻して
and nothing in between. This is useful
その間は何もありません。これは
for 2D games that need precise control
2D ゲームにおいて、スムージングされた値より
rather than smoothed values.
正確なコントロールが必要な場合に便利です。
Note that this does not require the use
これは Gravity または Sensitivity を必要としない
of gravity or sensitivity.
ことを覚えておくべきです。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)